<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brenna Briles</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brenna Briles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Brenna Briles is a 22 year old graduating senior at the University of Texas at Austin. She was born in College Station, Texas and moved to Austin for college. She is pursuing a Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology with minors in Sociology and Women and Gender Studies. After graduation, she will be attending medical school in the fall of 2020. She will be the first person in her family to earn a professional degree and to become a physician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice with Python</title>
      <link>/blog/practice-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/practice-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This post contains sample problems using Python from homework assignments in SDS348: Computational Biology and Bioinformatics instructed by Nathaniel Woodward and taken at the University of Texas at Austin.
NumPy Load the dataset faithful. Import numpy and use functions from it to compute the mean, median, and variance for each variable. Compute the correlation between the two variables using corrcoef.
import csv eruptions = [] waiting = [] with open(&amp;#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Resume Here&#39;s my resume:
 Resume  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on:
  Project 1
  Project 2
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling and Exploration</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The “follicle” dataset contains information regarding follicle formation in women of varying ages. It includes variables “Age” which is the age of the woman at the time of follicle counting, “Count” which is the number of follicles in the ovaries, and “Source” which is the source of the data. The “Pima.te” dataset contains information gathered from a population of women of Pima Indian descent. It contians variables “npreg” for number of pregnancies, “glu” for plasma glucose concentration in an oral glucose tolerance test, “bp” for diastolic blood pressure in mmHg, “skin” for skin fold thickness in millimeters, “bmi” for body mass index, “ped” for diabetes pedigree function, “age” for age in years, and “type” for diabetic status (yes or no).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The CPS85 dataset contains information relating wage in US dollars, number of years of education (edu), across categories of race, sex, Hispanic ethnicity, marriage status, years of work experience (exper), worker union membership (union), age, region of residence (south), and work sector. This data was gathered from the Current Population Survey in 1985. I chose this dataset because I am interested to see what relationships arise between education, race, and sex as well as relationships between wages, marriage, and union memberships.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>